Claudio Atilano

claudio@metamesh.io | (786) 663-0320 | http://claudioatilano.com

Summary

I am a Full Stack Developer with 3 years of experience. I can identify the need for a solution and communicate with users to create their desired solution. I am self-disciplined in creating applications under a given timeline and focused on constant product iterations.

Skills

- MongoDB
- Express.js
- ReactJS
- React Native
- Node.js
- Oracle

- SQL
- Javascript
- Python
- HTML
- CSS
- Linux/Unix

- Java
- AWS EC2 Instance
- Git
- RESTful APIs
- AWS SES/SNS/SQS
- Maven

Work Experience

NextEra Energy

March 2019 - June 2020

Associate IT Programmer Analyst

Developed and designed a scalable data driven customer communication platform for NextEra Energy's newly acquired utility company, Gulf Power Company. This platform was programmed with Java using the spring framework and Javascript for their user interfaces.

- Led a team of 2 onsite developers and 3 offshore Java developers with Agile methodologies and tracked developments through JIRA.
- Developed a batch email sending module using AWS SES and Java to send over 10,000 email bills to customers.
- Upgraded 2 user interfaces that were using jQuery and Javascript to ReactJS.
- Trained new developers on the Java codebase and data driven processes.

Metamesh Inc.

Jan 2018 - March 2019

Co-Founder, Full Stack Software Developer

Founded company dedicated to helping people sell products with peer-to-peer marketing incentives through a progressive web application. Metamesh is a social marketplace for geeks that launched in November with roughly 300 users. More information at https://metamesh.io.

- Hired and managed a skilled team to build a social commerce progressive web app.
- Managed development cycles, company vision and product iterations.

- Programmed a RESTful API using Node.js, MongoDB and Stripe for monetary transactions with JSON Web Token authentication.
- Designed and developed an elegant responsive front end using ReactJS, HTML, CSS and Javascript that can be downloaded as a progressive web app.

Projects

Bitcore-insight Jan 2019 - Present

http://npmjs.com/package/bitcore-insight

While I was at the Miami Bitcoin Hackathon I realized it was difficult to get started with Bitcoin transactions. That's why I forked an old repo and created appropriate documentation for Javascript developers that wanted to get started right away with Bitcoin.

• Published a well documented package on npm for Javascript developers to code Bitcoin transactions can be seen in the link above.

Naruto CCG Community Application

Jan 2019 - Present

https://app.narutoccg.com

I identified the need for a community app for the Naruto CCG community. I developed and deployed an Android and iOS application with React Native that has 80 daily active users and 500 weekly active users.

- Created a RESTful API for card data using Express.js Node.js and MongoDB and deployed it on an AWS Linux EC2 instance
- Maintained versioned code that was backwards compatible for prior mobile application downloads
- Implemented a realtime chat feature using web sockets with push notifications for community members to communicate with each other across mobile clients with React Native.

Education

Python Neural Networks and Deep Learning

Oct 2017

Coursera Certificate

HTML, CSS & Javascript Mobile Sites

June 2017

Google Certificate

Bachelor of Arts, Physics

May 2017

Cum Laude

Florida International University

Miami, FL